<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Recipe>
  <Title image="Braising_Braising.jpg" name="Braising" category="TECHNIQUE" cuisine="ALL">
    <Yield amount="" units="BAG"/>
    <Times prep="0" cook="0"/>
  </Title>
  <Nutrition calories="" fat="" carbs="" protein="" sugar="" sodium="" fiber="" servings="" servingsUnit="CUP"/>
  <Description>It's hard to go wrong with steaks on the grill or a nice roast because you are usually starting out with a good cut of meat to begin with and its mainly a matter of not messing up and cinderizing it.  But what do you do with an old shank of lamb, tough old shoulder cuts or briskets of beef, bony ribs and the like?  Braising.  Braising is cool.  Braising rescues destined-for-shoesole cuts of meat and turns them into succulent treasures.  It's not a particularly complicated thing, but it does require attention to detail and an investment in time.  And its one of those cooking techniques that responds well to tinkering and provides plenty of opportunity to do just that.  So there's a direct correlation between the amount of time and effort you put into it and the quality of the end result, in a way that doesn't necessarily require a lot of skill and experience to begin with, yet provides it all the same -and that can be unusually rewarding.

Braising, in a nutshell, consists of:  Surface searing (browning) of the meat by high heat, often after dredging in flour, followed by long, slow cooking over low heat in a small amount of liquid, typically over a bed of aromatic vegetables.

But there can be endless variations.  You can marinade the meat prior to cooking in as many ways as you can imagine.  You can use dry rubs for seasoning.  You can season flour for dredging.  You can choose the type of fat used to brown the meat (clarified butter &amp; olive oil, sesame oil, bacon fat ...) You have to decide what kind of stock to use for the simmering stage.  You have to decide what vegetables to use.  You can do the cooking in several stages, changing the cooking liquids, straining and clarifying it, and changing the vegetable beds.  You must pick and adjust seasonings.  After cooking you can sauce, you can use a reduction of the cooking liquid or use a different sauce altogether.  You can spend all day playing with it if you want to.  The more you put into it, the more you get out of it. </Description>
  <Prerequisites/>
  <Ingredients/>
  <Method/>
  <Variations/>
</Recipe>